# VAN CHAN NGO

+1412-626 0329  $\diamond$ channgo@cmu.edu $\diamond$ van-chan.ngo(Skype) Carnegie Mellon University, 5000 Forbes Avenue, PA 15213, USA

http://channgo2203.github.io/

#### **SUMMARY**

My research activities aim at building reliable and secure computer systems by developing formal frameworks which guarantee that software satisfies formally its specification, especially embedded safety-critical software such as automotive, avionic, and health-care applications. The construction of a formal framework involves the research and knowledge of principles of programming languages, compiler design and development, and formal methods including model checking, theorem proving, and static analysis for providing formal assurances that the specification is fulfilled.

#### **EDUCATION**

## INRIA, Rennes, France

August 2014

Ph.D in Computer Science & Engineering

Programming Language, Compiler, and Formal Verification of Embedded and Safety-Critical Systems First Class Honors

## Université de Grenoble, Verimag, Grenoble, France

June 2008

Masters in Computer Science & Engineering

Embedded Software and Systems

French Government Scholarship, Évariste Galois Program

## Hanoi University of Technology, Hanoi, Vietnam

July 2005

Engineer Degree in Computer Engineering

Information Systems and Communication, Centre of Talented Training - PFIEV

First Class Honors with Congratulations of the Ministry of Education

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Carnegie Mellon University

2016 - Present

Research Fellow, Computer Science

Pittsburgh, PA, US

- · Automatic symbolic resource bound (e.g., time and memory) analysis of functional and imperative programs for detecting security vulnerability including time side-channel attacks, stack overflow, etc
- · Static analysis for probabilistic programs, e.g., automatic symbolic expected resource bound analysis such as execution time and memory usage

INRIA France

2014 - 2015

R&D Engineer

Rennes, France

- $\cdot$  Formal verification of probabilistic System C models using Statistical Model Checking
- · Probabilistic temporal assertion-based verification of SystemC models

INRIA France
2011 - 2014
Research Assistant
Rennes, France

- · Formal verification of the highly optimizing and industrial synchronous compiler, Signal, which is used in model-based design of real-time and safety-critical systems
- · Using translation validation approach to prove the preservation of clock semantics, data dependencies and value-equivalence for source code and the compiled programs using several techniques including model checking, theorem proving, graph transformation

Tech Propulsion Lab USA

Software Architect Saigon Branch, Vietnam

· Design and development of embedded mobile software on iOS and Android platforms

· Project management in the mobile development department

## IBM Zurich Lab and ZISC

2008 - 2010

2010 - 2011

Research Assistant

Zurich. Switzerland

· Formally verifying and certifying the design of secure boot processes in IBM AIX mainframes

 $\cdot \ \ \text{Formalizing the boot process and its security properties using the language of the model checker Spin, Promela.}$ 

Verimag Lab

2007 - 2008

Internship

Grenoble, France

· Automated verification framework to prove formally the IND-CPA security property of asymmetric encryption schemes

· The framework represents the encryption schemes as frame in cryptographic  $\pi$ -calculus, and formalize the IND-CPA property as a equivalent relation between two frames

IBM Vietnam 2006 - 2007

Senior Software Engineer

Hanoi, Vietnam

Hanoi, Vietnam

· Working on text search engine of the IBM data base management DB2

FPT Software 2005 - 2006

Software Engineer

· Working on embedded systems for navigation

# Security Systems, MISOFT

2003 - 2005

Software Developer

Hanoi, Vietnam

· Developing a distributed firewall as an operation system based on the package filtering library and the Linux kernel in C++ and Python

# Hanoi University of Technology

2000 - 2003

Tutor

Hanoi, Vietnam

· Student teaching in Mathematics and Physics

## TECHNICAL STRENGTHS

- · Programming Languages. Strong knowledge: C/C++, OCaml Familiarity: Assembly, Java, Python
- · Toolchains. Strong knowledge: GCC, LLVM Compiler Infrastructure
- · Formal Methods & Modeling Languages. Strong knowledge: Synchronous Languages, Logics and Temporal Logics, Model Checking, Theorem Proving, Static Analysis Familiarity: Verilog, SystemC
- · Formal Method Tools. SPIN, SMV, UPAAL, PRISM, SMC Plasma Lab, Yices, Z3, Coq, Frama-C
- · Embedded Software Development. Familiarity: AVR, Arduino, RTLinux, FreeRTOS

# **PUBLICATIONS**

#### **Journals and Conferences**

· V.C. Ngo, M. Dehesa-Azuara, M. Fredrikson, J. Hoffmann. Verifying and Synthesizing Constant-Resource Implementations with Types. To appear in 2017 IEEE Symposium on Security & Privacy (SP Oakland'17). IEEE, San Jose, CA, USA, May 2017 [PDF]

- · V.C. Ngo and A. Legay. Formal Verification of Probabilistic System C Models with Statistical Model Checking. In Journal of Software: Evolution and Process. Wiley, 2016 (under review) [PDF]
- · V.C. Ngo, A. Legay, and V. Joloboff. *PSCV: A Runtime Verification Tool for Probabilistic SystemC Models*. In Proceedings of 28th International Conference on Computer Aided Verification (**CAV'16**). Springer, Toronto, Ontario, Canada, July 2016 [PDF]
- · V.C. Ngo, A. Legay, and J. Quilbeuf. Statistical Model Checking for System C Models. In Proceedings of 17th High Assurance Systems Engineering Symposium (HASE'16). IEEE, Orlando, Florida, USA, January 2016 [PDF]
- · V.C. Ngo, J-P. Talpin, T. Gautier, L. Besnard, and P. Le Guernic. *Modular Translation Validation of a Full-sized Synchronous Compiler using Off-the-shelf Verification Tools*. In Proceedings of International Workshop on Software and Compilers for Embedded Systems (**SCOPES'15**). ACM, St. Goar, Germany, June 2015 [PDF]
- · V.C. Ngo, J-P. Talpin, and T. Gautier. Translation Validation for Synchronous Data-flow Specification in the SIGNAL Compiler. In Proceedings of 35th IFIP International Conference on Formal Techniques for Distributed Objects, Components and Systems (FORTE'15). IFIP, Grenoble, France, June 2015 [PDF]
- · V.C. Ngo, J-P. Talpin, T. Gautier, and P. Le Guernic. *Translation Validation for Clock Transformations in a Synchronous Compiler*. In Proceedings of 18th International Conference on Fundamental Approaches to Software Engineering (**FASE'15**). Springer, London, UK, April 2015 [PDF]
- · V.C. Ngo, J-P. Talpin, and T. Gautier. Precise Deadlock Detection for Polychronous Data-flow Specifications. In Proceedings of the Electronic System Level Synthesis Conference (ESLsyn-DAC'14). IEEE, San Francisco, CA, USA, June 2014 [PDF]
- · V.C. Ngo, J-P. Talpin, T. Gautier, P. Le Guernic, and L. Besnard. Formal Verification of Synchronous Dataflow Program Transformations Toward Certified Compilers. In Journal of Frontiers of Computer Science. Special Issue on Synchronous Programming, Springer, 2013 [PDF]
- · V.C. Ngo, J-P. Talpin, T. Gautier, P. Le Guernic, and L. Besnard. Formal Verification of Automatically Generated C-code from Polychronous Data-flow Equations. Accepted at International High-Level Design, Validation and Test Workshop (HLDVT'12). IEEE, California, USA, November 2012 [PDF]
- · V.C. Ngo, J-P. Talpin, T. Gautier, P. Le Guernic, and L. Besnard. Formal Verification of Compiler Transformations on Polychronous Equations. In Proceedings of 9th International Conference on Integrated Formal Methods (IFM'12). Springer, Pisa, Italy, June 2012 [PDF]
- · C. Ene, Y. Lakhnech, and V.C. Ngo (Authors by alphabetical order). Formal Indistinguishability Extended to the Random Oracle Model. In Proceedings of 14th European Symposium on Research in Computer Security (ESORICS'09). Springer, Saint-Malo, France, September 2009 [PDF]
- · C. Ene, Y. Lakhnech, and V.C. Ngo (Authors by alphabetical order). Formal Indistinguishability Extended to the ROM. In Proceedings of Workshop on Formal and Computational Cryptography (FCC'09), New York, USA, July 2009 [PDF]

## Thesis

· V.C. Ngo. Formal Verification of a Synchronous Data-flow Compiler: from Signal to C. In **Ph.D Thesis** in Computer Science, INRIA France, University of Rennes, France, July 2014 [PDF]

- · V.C. Ngo. Automated Verification of Asymmetric Encryption. In M.Sc Thesis in Computer Science and Applied Mathematics, VERIMAG, University of Grenoble, France, June 2008 [PDF]
- · V.C. Ngo. Theory and Implementation of Distributed Firewall on Linux Environment (in Vietnamese). In **Engineer Thesis** in Computer Engineerings, Center for Talent Training, Hanoi University of Technology, Vietnam, July 2005

## **Technical Reports**

- · M. Fredrikson, J. Hoffmann, and V.C. Ngo. Quantifying and Preventing Side Channels with Substructural Type Systems. In CMU, Technical Report, June 2016 [PDF]
- · V.C. Ngo, A. Legay, and J. Quilbeuf. Dependability Analysis of Embedded Control Systems Using SystemC and Statistical Model Checking. In HAL INRIA, Technical Report RR-8762, July 2015 [PDF]
- · V.C. Ngo, A. Legay, and J. Quilbeuf. Dynamic Verification of System C Specification with Statistical Model Checking. In HAL INRIA, Technical Report RR-8644, October 2014 [PDF]
- · V.C. Ngo, J-P. Talpin, T. Gautier, and P. Le Guernic. Evaluating SDVG Translation Validation: from Signal to C. In HAL INRIA, Technical Report RR-8508, March 2014 [PDF]
- · V.C. Ngo, J-P. Talpin, and P. Le Guernic. Formal Verification of Transformations on Abstract Clocks in Synchronous Compilers. In HAL INRIA, Technical Report RR-8064, September 2012 [PDF]
- · V.C. Ngo, J-P. Talpin, T. Gautier, P. Le Guernic, and L. Besnard. Formal Verification of Synchronous Dataflow Compilers. In HAL - INRIA, **Technical Report RR-7921**, April 2012 [PDF]

# AWARDS

Ph.D scholarship, INRIA France

DEA scholarship from the French government, Université de Grenoble, France

Masters scholarship from the Italian government, Politecnico di Milano, Italy

Masters scholarship from SamSung company, ICU-KAIST, South Korea

Scholarships from Hanoi University of Technology for excellent academic results

## **SOFTWARES**

• RAML: Resource Aware ML is a tool that automatically and statically computes bounds on resource usage (lower, constant, and upper bounds) for functional programs. It also can check the constant resource-use programs used in preventing timing side-channel attacks.

Website: http://www.raml.co

- · **PSCV**: A runtime verification tool for probabilistic SystemC models. It consists of two components: the plug-in for Plasma Lab in Java and tool for generating C++ monitor and aspect advices in C++. Website: https://project.inria.fr/pscv/
- · Plasma Lab: Plasma Lab is a compact, efficient and flexible platform for statistical model checking of stochastic models.

Website: https://project.inria.fr/plasma-lab/

· **Polychrony**: The Polychrony tool-set developed in C++ and Java, based on Signal, provides a formal framework to design, develop and validate critical systems, from abstract specification until deployment on distributed systems

Website: http://www.irisa.fr/espresso/Polychrony/

· **SigCert**: The tool developed in OCaml checks the correctness of the compilation of Signal compiler w.r.t clock semantics, data dependence, and value-equivalence (not fully implemented).

Website: https://github.com/channgo2203/sigcert

· SigCV: PDS Simulation Relation Checking with SIGALI: implementation of the theory works in IFM 2012 article as the libraries in SIGALI tool-set.

Website: https://github.com/channgo2203/SigCV

Mobile Applications: Mobile applications: RATP, Turnstone, Saigon Places, A86, PhotoEnc,...

Website: Apple Store

## **TEACHING**

- · Mechanizing Soundness Proofs of the Automatic Amortized Resource Analysis, Student project in Computer Science, Carnegie Mellon University, 2016
- · Introduction to Model Checking, Teaching assistant, Master in Computer Science, University of Rennes 1, 2013
- · Automaton-based Modeling and Formal Verification, Teaching assistant, Master in Computer Science, University of Rennes 1, 2012
- · High School Student Teaching in Mathematics and Physics, Tutor, Hanoi University of Technology, 2000-2003

#### RESEARCH PROJECTS

#### DANSE

· Summary: DANSE focuses on the development of a new methodology to support evolving, adaptive and iterative System of Systems (SoS) life-cycle models based on a formal semantics for SoS inter-operations and supported by novel tools for analysis, simulation, and optimisation.

DANSE includes industrial representatives with focus on aerospace, land, and automotive systems, as well as a leading tools and framework provider in the system space, and top European research institutes in system engineering. These partners have deep interest in the outcome of the research and are eager to deploy the developments as soon as they become available.

· Link: http://www.danse-ip.eu/home/

#### **DALI**

- · Summary: The DALI project has undertaken a challenging agenda aimed at extending the people autonomous life beyond the home. The environment where the system operates is partially known (due to its large variability) and changing. Our assisted living device system must therefore acquire dynamic information about the user's immediate environment in order to guide its decision-making. The construction of a system of such complexity represents a major scientific and technological effort bringing together expertise across different disciplines.
- · Link: http://www.ict-dali.eu/dali/

## VERISYNC

· Summary: The project proposed here aims at substantially improving the safety and reliability of embedded software that is being developed in the context of a Model-based design approach. This is achieved by formally proving the correctness of essential transformations that a model undergoes during its compilation to executable code. The definition of the semantics and the correctness proof of the compiler will be carried out by means of theorem proving. The compiler is executable and will be evaluated on realistic examples.

The project is targeted at the compilation of a synchronous language to an imperative programming language. Synchronous languages have turned out to be an expressive formalism for embedded algorithms, and their precise semantics make them particularly suitable for our purpose.

· Link: http://www.irit.fr/~Martin.Strecker/Proj/Old/Verisync/

#### **SCALP**

· Summary: Our day-to-day lives increasingly depend upon information and our ability to manipulate it securely. That is, in a way that prevents malicious elements to subvert the available information for their own benefits. This requires solutions based on cryptographic systems (primitives and protocols). However, no matter how carefully crafted cryptographic systems are, experience has shown that effective attacks can remain hidden for years. This may be caused by poor design or often unclear and poorly defined security properties and assumptions.

Therefore, provable security, where new systems are published with a rigorous definition of their security goals and a mathematical proof that they meet their goals, is being increasingly advocated. While the adoption of provable security significantly increases, the complexity and diversity of designed systems tend to increase too. Hence, it is largely agreed on that the point has been reached where it is no longer viable to construct or verify cryptographic proofs by hand (Bellare & Rogaway 2004, Shoup 2004, Halevi 2005) and that there is a need for computer-aided verification methods for cryptographic systems. The goal of this project is to achieve a major step towards building automated tools for the verification of cryptographic systems. In order, to reconcile generality, imposed by the high diversity of cryptographic systems, and automation, we shall build our tools upon Coq.

· Link: http://scalp.gforge.inria.fr/

## AVOTE

- · Summary: Electronic voting promises the possibility of a convenient, efficient and secure facility for recording and tallying votes. However, the convenience of electronic elections comes with a risk of large-scale fraud and their security has seriously been questioned. In this project we propose to use formal methods to analyze electronic voting protocols.
- $\cdot$  Link: http://www-verimag.imag.fr/AVOTE.html

# **TALKS**

- · PSCV: A Runtime Verification Tool for Probabilistic SystemC Models. Talk at CAV 2016, Toronto, Ontario, Canada, July 2016
- · Translation Validation for Synchronous Data-flow Specification in the SIGNAL Compiler. Talk at FORTE DisCoTec 2015, Grenoble, France, June 2015
- · Translation Validation for Clock Transformations in a Synchronous Compiler. Talk at FASE ETAPS 2015, London, UK, April 2015
- · Case Study: Dependability Analysis of Embedded Control Systems using SystemC and Statistical Model Checking. Talk at INRIA Rennes, France, March 2015
- · Precise Deadlock Detection for Polychronous Data-flow Specifications. Talk at ESLsyn DAC 2014, San Francisco, CA, USA, June 2014
- · Seminar: Compilation and Execution of Streaming Programs. St Germain au Mont d'Or, France, April 2014
- · Formal Verification of Transformations on Clocks in Synchronous Data-flow Compilers. Talk at 19th Open International Workshop on Synchronous Programming 2012, Le Croisic, France, November 2012

- · Formal Verification of Transformations on Clocks in Synchronous Data-flow Compilers. Invited Talk at Beihang University (BUAA), Beijing, China, October 2012
- · Formal Verification of Compiler Transformations on Polychronous Equations. Talk at IFM 2012, Pisa, Italy, June 2012
- $\cdot$  Formal Indistinguishability Extended to the Random Oracle Model. Talk at ESORICS 2009, Le Croisic, France, September 2009

#### PROFESSIONAL SERVICE

## **Review Activity**

- · The ACM SIGPLAN Conference on Programming Language Design and Implementation (PLDI17), Barcelona, Spain, June 2017
- · The 26th International Conference on Compiler Construction (CC17), Austin, Texas, US, February 2017
- · The 16th International Conference on Formal Methods in Computer-Aided Design (FMCAD16), Mountain View, CA, US, October 2016
- · The 27th International Conference on Concurrency Theory (CONCUR16), Quebec City, Canada, August 2016
- · The 13th ACM-IEEE International Conference on Formal Methods and Models for System Design (MEM-OCODE15), Austin, US, September 2015
- · The 8th International Conference on Language and Automata Theory and Applications (LATA14), Madrid, Spain, March 2014

#### **LANGUAGES**

English - Adva	ance Fren	nch - Advance	Vietnamese - Mother-tongue			
INTERESTS						
Instrumental	Painting	Running	Photography	Cooking	Robotic	